<Document>
  # Diona

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobDiona" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Plantfolk originating from the deadly verdant parasite known as the Megabriar. Diona share many traits with plants themselves, and hereditary remnants of the Megabriar allow them to reform as Nymphs upon death.

  ## Species Traits
  - Damage Resistances: Blunt/Piercing -40%, Slash -30%
  - Damage Weaknesses: Heat +50%, Shock +20%
  - Cannot wear shoes
  - Become hungry half as quickly, but become thirsty 50% faster
  - Catch fire when taking 12 or more Heat damage
  - Take Brute damage from PlantBGone and Poison damage from weedkiller
  - Nearly twice as heavy as a standard humanoid

  ## Species Abilities
  ### Nymphs
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobDionaNymph" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobDionaNymph" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobDionaNymph" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  After death, a Diona can voluntarily destroy their own body, releasing their "internal organs" as three Nymphs, with the player taking control of the Brain Nymph. It can talk but has no hands or inventory, and can't do much.

  After 10 minutes, a Nymph can reform into a whole Diona. This will be a new randomised body with a random name, and there will be little to no evidence beyond their word about who they were before.

  ### Rooting
  Diona can use their Rootable action to toggle a rooting mode, which works similarly to magboots; you move a little bit slower but stay firmly on the ground and can't be slipped by anything you walk over. This also causes Diona to drink from any puddles they walk or stand over, transferring its reagents directly into their bloodstream!

  ### Overgrowth
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FloraTree" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  Being exposed to too much Robust Harvest will cause a Diona to grow out of control, turning into an immobile tree and dropping all of their equipment. Cutting down the tree will reduce the Diona back down to normal.

  ## Naming Traditions
  Diona refer to themselves by a title they devise upon awakening to sapience. Traditionally, these names follow a format of "The (X) of (Y)", where X is a noun inspired by the place of the Diona's awakening, and Y is a noun inspired by the first feeling to move them.

  Examples:
  - The Rustling of Humility
  - The Glade of Joy
  - The Corridor of Grief
</Document>
